Okay, now we are going to add some scallops.
We are going to come back about halfway.
You can mark the halfway point between each of the scallops that you have with some pins.
And then, we are going to come back.
So, you just slide your needle through along the seam and come out at your marked point.
And, again we will measure off with our paper the amount of beads that we want for our scallop.
Okay.
And, hold that taut and just slide the needle through the beads.
When you hold the string nice and taut the needle will go right through easily.
Okay, you pull.
Okay, and then just pull it off of the pre-strung beads.
Okay, and now we will come to our next marked off point.
Okay, you want to go in and out like this.
Okay, and now you have got a little crisscrossed swag going on.
It is very pretty.
Okay, and we will do one more.
I am going to secure this pre-strung beads here and measure it off.
It has got just the right amount of beads on it.
And, slide your needle very slowly and you kind of watch the beads as the needle goes through.
You can see it enter each of the beads.
If you see the needle come out at the side, then you want to pull back and redo it.
Let me cut the knot off of the pre-strung beads and pull that up and go to our next marked off section.
And, you will just continue that to the end and we will secure each scallop as we go.
Okay, now when you get to the point where your thread is about twice the length of your needle you want to stop.
Do not be tempted to continue to bead till you are too close to the needle, because you need room to make your knot.
So, to make the knot we want to just come up through the fabric a little bit.
Grab a little bit of fabric.
You make a loop.
You put your needle through the loop and hold the next loop while you pull down the first loop.
And then, put your needle again through the loop and pull that down and pull the whole thing taut.
That should make a good secure knot.
And, you can cut off close to the knot.